

export const questions = [
    {
      question: "1.What is the capital of France?",
      options: ["Paris", "London", "Berlin", "Madrid"],
      correctAnswer: "Paris",
    },
    {
      question: "2.What is 2 + 2?",
      options: ["3", "4", "5", "6"],
      correctAnswer: "4",
    },
    {
        question: "3.Analytical Engine, the first fully automatic calculating machine was developed by",
        options: ["Charles Babbage", " Blaise Pascal", "Leibniz", "John Von Neumann"],
        correctAnswer: "Charles Babbage",
      },
      {
        question: "4.Which was the first mechanical calculating device?",
        options: ["UNIVAC", "Abacus", "PASCALINE", "Curta"],
        correctAnswer: "Abacus",
      }, {
        question: "5.Abacus can perform",
        options: ["Addition", "Subtraction", " Multiplication", "Both (a) and (b)"],
        correctAnswer: "Both (a) and (b)",
      },
      {
        question: "6. Pascaline is a",
        options: [" Abacus", " Adding Machine", "Difference Machine", "Multiplication Machine"],
        correctAnswer: " Adding Machine",
      }, {
        question: "7. Which of the following is known as the father of computers?",
        options: [" Dennis Ritchie","Napier","Charles Babbage"," Alan Turing"],
        correctAnswer: "Charles Babbage",
      },
      {
        question: "8. Analytical Engine invented during the first generation of computer used which memory unit?",
        options: ["RAM", "Floppies", "Counter wheels", "Cards"],
        correctAnswer: "Counter wheels",
      }, 
      {
        question: "9. The first electromechanical machine “Tabulating machine” was invented by",
        options: [" Herman Hollerith", "John Napier", "Howard Aiken", " Pascal"],
        correctAnswer: " Herman Hollerith",
      }, 
      {
        question: "10. Who designed the first electronic computer- ENIVAC?",
        options: ["Von Neumann", " Presper Eckert and John W Mauchly", "Joseph M Jacquard and John W Mauchly", " None of these"],
        correctAnswer: " Presper Eckert and John W Mauchly",
      }, 
      
  ];

  